	<chapter>
    	<title>Usage of the tools</title>
    	<para>Here we are going to explain what we want to build using the tools of universAAL and build it up by using them. Some tools
    	are not developed currently, but I think we should already mention them below and give them a place in the development-process.
    	Maybe not all tools are important (for example the transformation tools are only in "idea phase" and not design), but for the
    	most the usage is quite clear and it make sense to give them a place for D3.6-B already.</para>
    	<section>
    		<title>What we are going to do</title>
    		<para>We refer to D2.4 and and give hints to the existing code example of the lighting example. But before we
    		spend some general word about what should be the goal of the example (we want control lightsources in a distributed
    		system, therefore we need a server and a client, ....).</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Build up a new project</title>
    		<para>Here we can explain the creation of a new project by using the appropriate plugin. We need to build two projects
    		here, one for the server and one for the client. Still remember to not go into details about server and client,
    		that has been done in D2.4. Here we only explain why and how we build this projects and give names to them using the tool.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Add items</title>
    		<para>This is the section where we will explain the usage of the Project and Item Wizards. Here we can reuse what we already have
    		from the wiki and the current version of the tutorial. We need to add a service to control the light-sources to the service project.
    		So we will use the tool the add the appropriate service and name it according to the existing example from D2.4. We should mention
    		the basic methods and creation of service-profiles, but since we are currently have no tools that support this step we should once
    		more refer to the according chapter of 2.4 in the end.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Add items</title>
    		<para>This is the section where we will explain the usage of the Project and Item Wizards. Here we can reuse what we already have
    		from the wiki and the current version of the tutorial. We need to add a service to control the light-sources to the service project.
    		So we will use the tool the add the appropriate service and name it according to the existing example from D2.4. We should mention
    		the basic methods and creation of service-profiles, but since we are currently have no tools that support this step we should once
    		more refer to the according chapter of 2.4 in the end.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Conformance</title>
    		<para>Explain how we are plaing to integrate the conformance tool, what basic functionality we would like to integrate
    		and how it can help us now to verify that the created programm in the step before (Server and Client project)is correct.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Deployment</title>
    		<para>Also here we should explain the idea of the deployment tool in a nutshell and spend some word about deployment to 
    		developer depot and using uStore.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Configuration Tool</title>
    		<para>This tool partially already exists. The basic idea is to extract parameters for application configuration out of
    		java annotations. The usage of this tool must be also a part of this tutorial. Currently the lighting example have no
    		parameter for configuration, but we can extend it and add for example the location of the lightsources to make this clear.</para>
    	</section>
	</chapter>