	<chapter>
		<title>Summary</title>
		<para>So finally lets have a look back over all we have done in this guide. We have learned some general stuff about universAAL. If we want to
		developing universAAL application there are several sources that can give us information or we need during development process:</para>
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<title></title>
			<listitem><para>The <ulink url="http://www.universaal.org/">universAAL Homepage</ulink></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>The main page if you are going to now details about the universAAL platform or want to participate at programming the
				platform is the GForage available at <ulink url="http://forge.universaal.org">http://forge.universaal.org</ulink></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Up to date information about the tools you can find in the tools Wiki at
			<ulink url="http://forge.universaal.org/mediawiki/index.php?title=uaaltools:Main_Page">http://forge.universaal.org/mediawiki/index.php?title=uaaltools:Main_Page</ulink></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>The developer depot at <ulink url="http://depot.universaal.org/">depot.universaal.org/</ulink> is the main information
				point if you are going to develop application for the universAAL platform</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para>To get a more detailed start into universAAL platform we strongly recommend to also have a look at the 
		<ulink url="http://forge.universaal.org/mediawiki/index.php?title=support:Quick_Start_Guide_0">Developer Handbook</ulink>.
		This gives a deeper view into the middleware, but without be aware of the tools presented in this guide.</para>
		
		<para>We have seen how the AAL Suite can be installed an our system and how we can use the first available tools to support the creation
		of an universAAL application that are based on OSGi-Bundles. Also the tools are able to build and start the new bundles by
		creating a run-configuration that includes all needed bundles from the universAAL middleware. Conformance and Deployment will also be
		a part of the supported steps in the development process, so you should keep this tools in mind to save work later on. Additional
		we have done first steps toward a generic user configuration that allows to parse XML-Configuration-Files out of your project by using
		Java-Annotations.</para>
		
		<para>All tools will be under construction in the next time and there will be a lot of changes and improvements during lifetime of
		universAAL project. So keep yourself up-to-date and make it easier to write distributed applications using universAAL.</para>
	</chapter>