	<chapter>
    	<title>Introduction</title>
    	<para>Welcome to the universAAL Tools guide. This document is going to introduce the available tools for the universAAL platform. 
    	We will start by giving a short overview about the general scope of the platform as well as useful links to more detailed information 
    	about the platform itself. In this document you will learn how you can use the existing tools to make your life easier during developing 
    	with universAAL and therefore save time as well as creating more robust programms.</para>
    
    	<section>
    	<title>The universAAL project</title>
    	<para>UniversAAL is a by the Europan Commission sponsored project that going to create a reference specification to control open systems 
    	in area of Ambient Assisted Living. Also a reference implementation of the general concept will be provided an offered under GPL license. 
    	So feel welcome to join the universAAL community at the <ulink url="http://www.universaal.org/"> universAAL homepage (www.universaal.org)</ulink>
    	if you want to be a part of our team. This page is the best one to get first information about the general scope and progress in universAAL.
    	All projects that are a part of universAAL currently are hosted with a <emphasis>GForge-Server</emphasis> at <ulink url="http://forge.universaal.org">http://forge.universaal.org</ulink>.
    	Here you can register for a new account and get access to all free available sources. The main project for this guide is called
    	"universAAL_Tools" and can be accessed directly from the main page. If you have a valid account at the developer page you can also
    	access the <ulink url="http://forge.universaal.org/mediawiki/index.php?title=uaaltools:Main_Page">Wiki-Pages</ulink> of the tools project.
    	Here you can get up-to-date information about current development process and further help about special tools.
    	An other important link is the one to the <emphasis>Developer-Depot</emphasis> at <ulink url="http://depot.universaal.org/">depot.universaal.org/</ulink>. Here
    	you can find all needed information about current development status in universAAL and will in future get the possibility to upload
    	application created by you into the integrated Nexus-Server (<ulink url="http://depot.universaal.org/nexus">depot.universaal.org/nexus</ulink>).
    	Also here is the central place to get all needed information for developing applications for the universAAL platform.
    	In opposite to the Developer-Depot there exists also a store for Apps called <emphasis>uStore</emphasis>. The idea behind this is that we have three
    	main steps during development. First you write the new application locally and test it out. Second you compile at to a bundle and upload it to
    	the Developer-Depot. At third a service-provider will offer your application in the uStore, maybe in combination with some hardware and 
    	human resources (like installation support, needed sensors, professional care-givers, ...).</para>
    	<para>For even more detailed information then you can find in the Developer Handbook or this Guide we refer to the Deliverables of the
    	universAAL project. All about the reference architecture you can find in D1.3 (current version is D1.3-C). More about evaluated requirements,
    	the stakeholder model and terminology of universAAL you can find in the other Deliverables with 1.X (X in {1,2,4}). Where the developer handbook
    	is a part of D2.4 you can also get further information from the other deliverables with 2.X. Detailed information about the tools described in
    	this guide you will find in all deliverables with 3.X.</para>
    	</section>
    	
    	<section>
    	<title>The tools from universAAL</title>
    	<para>To create a reference of a middleware that is able to handle complex context management, reasoning, user interaction and much more is 
    	one basic purpose of universAAL. But also the building of a strong community, including external developers, is within the scope. What we 
    	need to have here is not only a good middleware, but also tools that are going to support your work with universAAL. This means to make it 
   		as easy as possible to create new applications that running within the platform system and support you to make the development easy to understand
   		and robust to program. Currently all of the tools in development status and some only in design phase. But there are also first versions of some
   		tools available, as well as an existing Eclipse Update-Page that contains already a plug-in to support universAAL projects.
   		In Figure 1 we give a short first overview about the available and planned tools.</para>
   		
   		<figure>
			<title>Overview of the universAAL tools</title>
			<graphic width="300px" align="center" fileref="newmedia/installplugin/ToolsOverview.PNG"/>
		</figure>
   		
   		<para>Currently most tools are concentrated within the <emphasis>AAL Studio</emphasis> that are based on the Eclipse IDE.
   		Here are functionalities provided that are basic for development with universAAL of provide some kind of convenience.
   		For example the "Project and Item Wizards" contains possibilites to create new projects and put universAAL based classes into them.
   		The Developer Depot Client will offer a possibility to upload your application directly from Eclipse into the Developer Depot and Conformance
   		Tools allow to check if you newly created application fits the needs and standards of univerAAL. Managing of Developer Depot and the Eclipse Update
   		Page itself, as well as the uStore are also within the responsibility of the universAAL tools. Finally the <emphasis>Deployment and Personalization tools</emphasis>
   		cover the gap between End-User and Application by providing tools to download, install and configure application according to the special
   		needs of an AAL-System. Also tools to support changing of reasoning and service composition will be a part of this package. To get
   		a current state in development of all tools you can have a look into the Tools Wikipage at
   		<ulink url="http://forge.universaal.org/mediawiki/index.php?title=uaaltools:Main_Page">http://forge.universaal.org/mediawiki/index.php?title=uaaltools:Main_Page</ulink>
   		(need an account on GForge)</para>
   		</section>
   		
   		<section>
    	<title>The Developers Handbook</title>
   		<para>Therefore we are want to strictly separate between the documentation of the core platform functionality and
   		the guide for the tools developed to support developers. Detailed information about the middleware you can find in the <emphasis>universAAL Developer Handbook</emphasis>,
   		that is currently available in the <ulink url="http://forge.universaal.org/mediawiki/index.php?title=support:Quick_Start_Guide_0">Media-Wiki of the Support-Project</ulink>
   		on the GForge-Server. There some strong relationships between the documentation in the developers handbook and this guide. Where ever needed we
   		will refer to the handbook by using <emphasis>DH</emphasis> as a short-cut, followed by the number of the appropriate chapter (e.g. DH1 for the starting-page of
   		the handbook). Although we will summarize important aspects, we advise to read the Handbook before using this guide.</para>
   		</section>
		
	</chapter>