	<chapter>
    	<title>Introduction</title>
    	<para>Welcome to the universAAL Tools guide. This document is going to introduce the available tools for the universAAL platform. 
    	We will start by giving a short overview about the general scope of the platform as well as useful links to more detailed information 
    	about the platform itself. In this document you will learn how you can use the existing tools to make your life easier during developing 
    	with universAAL and therefore save time as well as creating more robust programms.</para>
    
    	<section>
    	<title>The universAAL project</title>
    	<para>UniversAAL is a by the Europan Commission sponsored project that going to create a reference specification to control open systems 
    	in area of Ambient Assisted Living. Also a reference implementation of the general concept will be provided an offered under GPL license. 
    	So feel welcome to join the universAAL community at the <ulink url="http://www.universaal.org/"> universAAL homepage (www.universaal.org)</ulink>
    	if you want to be a part of our team. Also there are existing </para>
    	<para>To create a reference of a middleware that is able to handle complex context management, reasoning, user interaction and much more is 
    	one basic purpose of universAAL. But also the building of a strong community, including external developeres, is within the scope. What we 
    	need to have here is not only a good middleware, but also tools that are going to support your work with universAAL. This means to make it 
   		as easy as possible to create new applications that running within the platform system and support you to make them easy to understand
   		and robust to program.</para>
   		</section>
   		
    	<db:itemizedlist>
			<db:listitem>Short overview about scope and basics of universAAL</db:listitem>
			<db:listitem>Special purposes of this tutorial</db:listitem>
			<db:listitem>Links to also available recources for information (like D2.4 and Wiki-Pages)</db:listitem>
		</db:itemizedlist>
	</chapter>