<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<book version="4.5" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
	<info>
		<title>Creating a first uAAL application</title>  
		<author>
			<personname>uAAL consurtium</personname>
		</author>
		<db:copyright>
			<db:holder>universAAL</db:holder>
    		<db:year>2011</db:year>
    	</db:copyright>
 	</info>

	<chapter id="Chapter1" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    	<title>Introduction</title>
    	<para> Like agreed in the telco I will give in the following an overview about the structure of this tutorial like I have in mind.
    	Here we have to consider the dependencies to D2.4-A as well as the work already done in the Wiki-pages. In general my suggestion
    	is not only to describe separated tools and repeat the same captions for everyone. We must embed the usage of the tools in a story
    	that give a reader the possibility to not only understand how a special tools will works, but also how it is embedded in the content
    	of the development process of universAAL</para>
    	<para>In the following I give the main chapters that fits my understanding, as well as the subchapters I propose and some comments about
    	the possible content. Feel free to add additional comments to all bullets and please give me feedback about your thoughts. Then we can
    	distribute rest of the work to be done. If I understand right you have only tomorrow left to work on this? If yes, simply do want you
    	can in this short time and I will add the rest.</para>
    
    	<para>The introductions should give a general overview about universAAL and the available tools. I suggest the following points to be
    	part of this</para>
   
    	<db:itemizedlist>
			<db:listitem>Short overview about scope and basics of universAAL</db:listitem>
			<db:listitem>Special purposes of this tutorial</db:listitem>
			<db:listitem>Links to also available recources for information (like D2.4 and Wiki-Pages)</db:listitem>
		</db:itemizedlist>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter>
    	<title>Technical Overview</title>
    	<para>In this chapter we include all the basic techical stuff that is the same for all tools. To this I would count the following:</para>
    	<db:itemizedlist>
    		<db:listitem>List of needed soft- and hardware to run this examples</db:listitem>
			<db:listitem>Links that explain how to install universAAL, Eclipse and plugin-in's for Eclipse,
						but refer more or less to D2.4 and available tutorials in the web. Here we can also use your part about the installer</db:listitem>	
			<db:listitem>Detailed install hints to every tool (can also be taken for your previous work</db:listitem>
			<db:listitem>Spend some word about the basic idea of an uAAL application (as OSGi bundle) and what is about uStore and
			developer depot</db:listitem>
		</db:itemizedlist>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter>
    	<title>Usage of the tools</title>
    	<para>Here we are going to explain what we want to build using the tools of universAAL and build it up by using them. Some tools
    	are not developed currently, but I think we should already mention them below and give them a place in the development-process.
    	Maybe not all tools are important (for example the transformation tools are only in "idea phase" and not design), but for the
    	most the usage is quite clear and it make sense to give them a place for D3.6-B already.</para>
    	<section>
    		<title>What we are going to do</title>
    		<para>We refer to D2.4 and and give hints to the existing code example of the lighting example. But before we
    		spend some general word about what should be the goal of the example (we want control lightsources in a distributed
    		system, therefore we need a server and a client, ....).</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Build up a new project</title>
    		<para>Here we can explain the creation of a new project by using the appropriate plugin. We need to build two projects
    		here, one for the server and one for the client. Still remember to not go into details about server and client,
    		that has been done in D2.4. Here we only explain why and how we build this projects and give names to them using the tool.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Add items</title>
    		<para>This is the section where we will explain the usage of the Project and Item Wizards. Here we can reuse what we already have
    		from the wiki and the current version of the tutorial. We need to add a service to control the light-sources to the service project.
    		So we will use the tool the add the appropriate service and name it according to the existing example from D2.4. We should mention
    		the basic methods and creation of service-profiles, but since we are currently have no tools that support this step we should once
    		more refer to the according chapter of 2.4 in the end.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Add items</title>
    		<para>This is the section where we will explain the usage of the Project and Item Wizards. Here we can reuse what we already have
    		from the wiki and the current version of the tutorial. We need to add a service to control the light-sources to the service project.
    		So we will use the tool the add the appropriate service and name it according to the existing example from D2.4. We should mention
    		the basic methods and creation of service-profiles, but since we are currently have no tools that support this step we should once
    		more refer to the according chapter of 2.4 in the end.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Conformance</title>
    		<para>Explain how we are plaing to integrate the conformance tool, what basic functionality we would like to integrate
    		and how it can help us now to verify that the created programm in the step before (Server and Client project)is correct.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Deployment</title>
    		<para>Also here we should explain the idea of the deployment tool in a nutshell and spend some word about deployment to 
    		developer depot and using uStore.</para>
    	</section>
    	<section>
    		<title>Configuration Tool</title>
    		<para>This tool partially already exists. The basic idea is to extract parameters for application configuration out of
    		java annotations. The usage of this tool must be also a part of this tutorial. Currently the lighting example have no
    		parameter for configuration, but we can extend it and add for example the location of the lightsources to make this clear.</para>
    	</section>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter>
	<title>Summary</title>
		<para>Reflect what we have done during this tutorial. Make a summary about the whole story and point out the basic aspects.
		Also have look at what really exists currently and what is in plannung.</para>
	</chapter>
</book>
